Juan P. Ayala Product Designer

I am a native smiler who loves creating meaningful design experiences and have cooperated with fantastic and talented people in both Irish and Venezuelan companies for the past 10 years.

Proficient in visual and UX/UI design, design thinking model, data analysis, coding, reporting, English, Spanish and Portuguese.

Skills

Figma, Sketch, Adobe Suite, Balsamiq, Zeplin, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, MS Office, Heap and R Programming.

Contact

- in www.linkedin.com/in/jp-ayala
- Be www.behance.net/ayalajuano
- https://uxfol.io/Ayalajuan
- Ayalajuano@gmail.com
- (n) Dublin, Ireland
- **©** 083-3034668

Education

2016 - 2018

BA in graphic designDublin Institute of Design
Dublin, Ireland

2008 - 2012 BS in Business Administration and Graphic Design Nueva Esparta University Caracas, Venezuela

Certifications

2021-2023

- R Coding for Data Science
- Intro to Web Accessibility
- Heap Foundations
- Speculative Design
- NNgroup: Influencing

Work experience

Senior Product Designer

Hertz, Ireland

Aug 2023 - Current

- Evaluate projects for better performance and usage of UX/UI standards.
- Process qualitative and quantitative data to refine flows, blueprint and user experience.
- Collaborate with multifunctional teams to produce responsive and multi-device designs.

Senior Product Designer

Goatpath by Software ONE, Ireland

Oct 2020 - Aug 2023

- Gathered user insights and data analytics to validate and inform design decisions.
- Created and share reports with stakeholders to enhance the platform's ease of use.
- Audited UX/UI and accessibility issues to create a better and more inclusive product.
- Conducted interviews and usability tests to optimize user goals and pain points.
- Lead LATAM UX/UI product solutions to support the roadmap's quality.
- Built HTML and Sketch prototypes for usability testing.
- Mentored a junior UX designer from our design team.

UX/UI Designer

ALTV Media, Ireland

Dec 2017 - Feb 2020

- Designed websites and apps using design thiking principles and improving their usability.
- Coded the National Broadband Ireland webapp and designed the Dugout Fire tv app.
- Conducted market research, personas creation, user journeys. and based-role designs.

UX/UI Designer

Meebler, Ireland

Sep 2016 - Jul 2017

- Designed and coded a website and app prototype for the Dublin Tech Summit 2017
- Expanded the company's branding and identity by creating strong visual elements.
- Carried out QA testing of the prototype app ensuring an intuitive and easy use.
- Contributed to developing user personas and journeys in team workshops.

UI Designer

Marketplace Connectors (Internship), Ireland

May 2016 - Sep 2016

- Designed responsive, multi-device and intuitive designs for the Connect.IO platform.
- Created marketing collateral, infographics and videos to develop the business initiatives.
- Led and created photographic material for social media and the company's website.

Career break

Freelancing, travelling, learning new languages.

UI Developer

Servicios Netosfera, Venezuela

May 2013 - Aug 2013

Sep 2013 - Apr 2016

- Designed, coded and maintained customer's corporate websites and marketing material.
- Advised clients on the development of their company's branding.

Graphic Designer

Super Eventos, Venezuela

Sep 2011 - Aug 2012

Created slides, POP material and interactive apps for Samsung, Cocacola and others clients.